# Changkun Ou

**J** +49 157 7214 1480 / +86 186 1322 5636

Online version: https://changkun.de/s/resume

Last updated: May 7, 2022

# Resume

@changkun 😯 changkun.de 🏶

# Introduction

I am a Ph.D. candidate in human-computer interaction at the Institute of Informatics, LMU Munich (Germany). My research is about human-in-the-loop 3D graphics systems in which I use machine learning to explore and exploit human preferences and improving their decision making. Thus, my research is in interdisciplying between machine learning, 3D graphics, and user modeling.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Ph.D. Student Media Informatics (Dr. rer. nat.)

Feb. 2019 - (exp.) Feb. 2023

LMU Munich

• Advisors: Prof. Dr. Andreas Butz (Erstberichterstatter), Prof. Dr. Eyke Hüllermeier (Zweitberichterstatter)

#### Master Student Human-Computer Interaction (M.Sc.)

Oct. 2016 - Jan. 2019

LMU Munich; overall grade: 1.63 (max. 1.0) between "Very Good" and "Good"

Munich, Germany

Munich, Germany

• Thesis: "Understanding and Predicting Web Browsing Behavior"

• Advisors: Dr. Daniel Buschek, Dr. Malin Eiband, Prof. Dr. Heinrich Hußmann

# Bachelor Student Computer Science and Engineering (B.Eng.)

Sep. 2012 - Jul. 2016

Southwest University for Nationalities; overall grade: 3.74 (max. 4.0), "Top 1" of 154 students

Chengdu, China

• Thesis: "Designing Alternative Contact-free Control Modalities for Smart Watches"

o Advisor: Prof. Dr. Yaxi Chen

#### **University Entrance Exam**

Sep. 2000 – Jul. 2012

Overall grade: 512 (max. 750, first/second/third tiers: 520/451/357).

Huaihua, China

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Research Associate Aprl. 2018 – Present

LMU Munich

Munich, Germany

- As researcher: research on human-in-the-loop machine learning 3D graphics systems
- · As teacher: teach 12 classes (as lecturer/instructor/assistant/tutor), and supervising 20+ student theses and seminars
- **As developer**: develop a 3D mesh processing backend system in collaboration with industry partner WAY digital solutions; develop, migrate, and maintain a 17 year-old university CMS system, and a 13 year-old collaborative system

#### **Backend Software Engineer (Remote)**

Apr. 2018 - Jan. 2019

LabEx Technology Ltd

Munich, Germany

- **As team leader**: leading developments of an oversea product; established microservice based backend architecture; the product autoscales cloud instances (on AWS/AlibabaCloud) ranging from 20 to 200; the product user group grows from 5k+ to 30k+ during my incumbency.
- As developer: 1) developed a scalable remote desktop proxy (support WebSocket to VNC/RDP/SSH protocols) using Go; 2) developed an
  automated multi-cloud resource management microservice that abstracts cross cloud providers (supports AWS/AlibabaCloud over 15 cloud
  products, e.g., IAM/EC2/VPC/etc), scales and used by 10k+ users; 3) developed a kubernetes-like container and instance hybrid management
  service.
- Involved techniques: Frontend: Vue, jQuery, Webpack, Electron; Backend: Go, Cgo, Gin, Beego, gRPC, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis,
   Hypervisor, Nginx, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, AlibabaCloud, etc

# **Fullstack Engineer (Freelance)**

Nov. 2017 - Mar. 2018

Rocketlingo UG

Munich, Germany

- **As developer**: developed a voice bot to support novice language learner to improve their language skills by real-time voice recognition and synthesis (supports web and Amazon Alexa), optimize for audio streaming and multilingual falt tolerances using machine learning
- Involved techniques: TypeScript; WebSocket; Angular; Google Cloud STT and TTS; Sklearn; Voice Recognition; etc

Page 1 of 2

# **OPEN SOURCE ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS**

A public statistics indicates that I have earned 18.2k+ stars, 14.2k+ total code commits, 30 contributed open source projects. A public contribution ranking indicates I am a **top 200 developer in Germany** or a **top 100 developer in China**. See github.com/changkun for more authored softwares (including frameworks/tools). Here lists a few selected activities and organizations:

- Go (organization member): an open sourced programming language developed by a team at Google, and have approx. 2 million developer users in the globe. I am one of the official Go organization member (163 people in total), current maintainer of x/mobile repository, active contributor to language runtime and standard library.
- fyne (core organization member): an open sourced cross platform GUI framework written in Go, and I am one of the organization member (12 people in total), mainly contributing to graphics and mobile drivers, performance improvements.
- The golang.design Initiative (founder): I created the organization. The organization currently hosts 25 software projects and 6 core members. The organization website have 465k+ page views and 66k+ historical viewers in total since Sep 2020.
- The TalkGo community (core organization member): I am a core member of the organization. The community organizes weekly public tech talks, currently have 6.35k+ subscribers, organized 132 public talks. I contributed 7 talks, and they are one of the most viewed talks.
- Juejin Translation Community (member): Major contributor, translated 50+ articles from English to Chinese.
- Occasional contributions: Tensorflow (164+ stars), etcd (39.6k+ stars), etc.

### **EXPERTISE AND SKILLS**

Expertise is context- and comparison-dependent. Here states the years of experience in terms of use, also indicates a subjective estimation of the level of expertise (either *intermediate*, *experienced*, or *expert*):

- Domain: Computer graphics (3D rendering and geometry processing, 3 years of Bachelors level teaching at university, 2 years of Masters level teaching, Blender/OpenGL/Metal/three.js, experienced); Machine learning (1 year of Masters level teaching at university, Andrew Ng's Deep Learning Specialization Certificate (ID: QGH8ZVJ6J2L2), Sklearn/Tensorflow/PyTorch/etc, intermediate); Data analysis (3 years of PhD research, numpy/seaborn/pandas/etc., experienced); Web development (2 years of industrial backend engineering, Go/React/etc., experienced).
- Language: Go (5 years+, expert); Python (4+ years, experienced); JavaScript/TypeScript (5+ years, experienced); C/C++ (2+ years, intermediate); ETeX (10+ years, experienced). I speak native Mandarin; fluent professional English; elementary German.

#### SCHOLARSHIPS AND AWARDS

ACM SIGCHI Special Recognitions (CHI '20) Outstanding Reviews	<b>Nov. 2019</b> <i>Munich, Germany</i>
Siemens AILab Hackathon 2nd Winner	<b>Nov. 2017</b> <i>Munich, Germany</i>
China National Scholarship University of Electronic Science and Technology of China	<b>Sep. 2016</b> Chengdu, China
Excellent Bachelor Thesis Award Southwest University for Nationalities	<b>Jun. 2016</b> Chengdu, China
Best University Graduates Award Southwest University for Nationalities	<b>Jan. 2016</b> Chengdu, China
China National Scholarship Southwest University for Nationalities	<b>Sep. 2014</b> Chengdu, China
Meritorious Winner in American Mathematical Contest in Modeling (MCM' 14)  Southwest University for Nationalities	<b>Apr. 2014</b> Chengdu, China